A Guide to the Horse Racing Papers of Marion duPont Scott 1908-1977
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Horse Racing Papers of Marion duPont Scott 1908-1977
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11092-d
This collection contains 8 volumes and ca. 30 items (1 Hollinger box).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
This collection pertains to the breeding and purchase of thoroughbred horses, a horse show, a dog show, and to the records of early jockey clubs in Tappanhannock, Richmond, and Norfolk, and stud books of nineteenth century horse breeders, H.A. Tayloe of Mount Airy and George H. Burwell of Carter Hall. Types of materials include bound volumes, letters, photographs, pedigrees, a dog show ribbon, promotional photographs showing the portraits of Alfred Jonniaux, and breeding records.
Contents List
- "Ardent Dancer" Pedigree & Letters re: Sale, with black & white photograph 1962-1965
- Best of Breed Ribbon from "Harrisburg Kennel Club, March 19, 1977," a memoranda book and a list of issues of Country Life1963, 1977, n.d.
- Examples of the Work of Portrait Painter, Alfred Jonniaux 1949-1951
- "Mongo" Breeding Records 1969-1970
- Montpelier Horse Show Programme 1908 Oct 19
- Pedigrees & Photographs of Irish Fillies for Sale in Dublin ca. 1976
- Photographs of Horses and a Dog by Raymond G. Woolfe, Bert & Richard Morgan Studio, William P. Gilbert and Peter A. Juley & Son n.d.
- Bound volume containing handwritten copy of the Newmarket Calendar of the stake races reported in C.M. Prior's Manuscript 1718-1751, Bound volume
- Bound volume containing a photostatic copy of the Tappahannock Jockey Club Minute Book, with some fragmentary accounts for 1796-1797, original at the Virginia Historical Society, Tayloe Papers 1796-1801, Bound volume
- Bound volume containing photostatic copies of 1) Stud Book of George H. Burwell (1799-1873) of Carter Hall, 1823-1828; 2) William Thornton letters to George H. Burwell, 1824-1833; 3) John Randolph of Roanoke horse letters, 1802-1805, 1828; and 4) William B. Johnson to Richard Singleton, 1833 1802-1833, Bound volume
- Bound volume containing a transcript of the Minute Book of the Richmond Jockey Club 1824-1835, Bound volume
- Bound volume containing a transcript of the Minute Book of the Norfolk Jockey Club 1826-1833, Bound volume
- Bound volume containing photostatic copy of the Stud Book of H.A. Tayloe, Mount Airy 1835-1840, Bound volume
- Bound volume containing a photostatic copy of the Minute Book of the Norfolk Jockey Club 1826-1833, Oversize bound volume